<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiences on Faran Meshinchi Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiences on Faran Meshinchi Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Student Technical Assistant - Facility for Rare Isotope Beams</title>
      <link>https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/frib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/frib/</guid>
      <description>Student Technical Assistant at FRIB Brief The Facility for Rare Isotope Beams is a scientific user facility for nuclear science at Michigan State University. In my role as a Student Technical Assistant, I worked with the mechanical design team to troubleshoot technical issues and automate design processes where necesssary.&#xA;Responsibilities Collaborated with engineers to diagnose and resolve integration issues between CAD and PDM software by replicating reported problems and testing potential solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SDE Intern - Amazon</title>
      <link>https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://meshinc1.github.io/experience/amazon/</guid>
      <description>Software Development Engineer Intern at Amazon Brief My internship at Amazon served as my first professional experience in software development. The role provided me insights into effective communication with my manager, the importance of understanding systems on a macroscopic level, and the intricacies of software design.&#xA;Responsibilities Developed a feature for the Alexa mobile app by modifying UI elements and existing APIs to improve the customer experience. Coordinated with team members and other developers during implementation and leveraged the collective knowledge to revise project-related changes during code reviews.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
